♪From primal chaos to the starry sky♪
♪In the whole world,
we shall hold the balance♪
♪The cauldron tempers divine blades♪
♪The furnace refines the empty void♪
♪The Way is in mystic fate♪
♪Be brave enough
to split the primal chaos wide open♪
[Pull Strings]
[Adapted from the novel
by Yan Gui Zheng Zhuan]
This isn't a threat.
I'm asking the Three Sects
to unite against this crisis.
The Three Sects unite?
Are you kidding me?
See for yourself.
Those Seizing Sect disciples
down there...
They're all puppets of demonic arts.
You're an Aureate Immortal.
Can't you see it?
Of course I can.
Today, the Seizing Sect
attacks the Human Sect.
And tomorrow?
The Elucidating Sect
attacks the Seizing Sect?
And the Human Sect
attacks the Elucidating Sect?
This vicious cycle repeats endlessly.
Is this really the Way
your mentor seeks?
You...
Right now, there's a force
that's the common enemy
of the Three Sects.
Their goal
is to make the Three Sects
tear each other apart.
Are you gonna wait
until the enemy bares their fangs
to regret standing by today?
Changgeng...
What exactly is he trying to do?
He needs to learn to trust.
Mentor.
My spiritual power is back.
Oh no.
The Pregenesis Sword
left the Ascendance Sect.
Changgeng.
What trick did you play?
My turn.
No more pretending.
Sea-Calming Pearls.
Sea-Calming Pearls?
Kill!
You're Zhao Gongming?
Kill.
Kill...
My fellow disciples,
this disaster
is my debt. Zhao Gongming owes you all.
In the next life,
we shall drink and be merry again.
Next life.
[Episode 21]
Pregenesis Sword.
Sorry...
Take the Pregenesis Sword.
For my rudeness.
What is this?
Why did Changgeng
tell me to protect it?
Ke Le'er.
Why are you still in boys' clothes?
I am a man.
You're a man?
Stop it.
Let's get to the point.
Do you still remember
what the Grandlord
of the Sea Deity Sect taught you?
We do.
Trust the Sea Deity, get great power.
Do you still believe
in the Sea Deity Sect?
We do.
Good.
Then follow me and fight our way back.
Prove your strength to the Grandlord.
Yes.
Let's go.
Your Highness.
The Pearl Elites will aid you.
Si'er?
Seeing you turn into a golden dragon,
I see the truth clearly now.
Our Mermaid Clan will follow you
to return to the East Sea
and revive the Dragon Clan.
Senior.
I swear I'll find you.
Mentor. Uncle.
Mentor.
What a pity.
If he could've worked for me,
it wouldn't have come to this.
Jade Division truly is poor.
Not even some decent tea.
Your mentor is dumb.
Your uncle is dumb.
And you are dumb, too.
You already escaped.
But you came back just to die.
I never thought my carefully laid plan
was foiled at the cost of your life.
Guess Qi Yuan taught you well.
Good thing Jiu Wu is already dead.
Next,
I just need to get rid of you.
Then no one will know my true identity.
I'll remain an Elder
of the Ascendance Sect.
With merit for defending the sect.
Whatever scheme I plan next,
no one can stop me.
Other way around, Elder Kuai.
I'm the one
who finally gets to kill you.
Kill me?
You're only an Ascension Stage disciple.
What can you do to me?
Li Changshou.
How'd you get so strong?
This is Jade Division.
My turf.
How could this be?
I sealed the vital point on your body.
You can't use spiritual power now.
You couldn't even tell?
How did you ever
become an Aureate Immortal?
I knew you were the mole all along.
I just never made a move.
If I wanted to,
I could have killed you anytime.
I could even
choose how and when you die.
And how long you'd suffer before dying.
It was my fault.
My constant indulgence
and evasion
that led to today's tragedy.
So,
I've decided to end your life.
How could this be?
When Cloudlink Hermit
came to the Ascendance Sect,
he only bowed to Detached Master.
Cloudlink Hermit only
respects Aureate Immortals.
So why didn't he bow to you?
Because he saw right through you.
You used someone else's power
for your Tribulation.
You're not a real Aureate Immortal.
I am an Aureate Immortal!
I am one!
I've sealed all your vitals.
Your demonic power is draining away too.
Take a guess.
Why that is.
Why?
Elder Kuai.
Don't you want
to properly undergo a tribulation
and be a real Aureate Immortal?
I'm making your dream come true.
What is this?
This is Elucidating's Treasure Pearl.
It holds a thousand years
of spiritual power.
I bet you want it.
Elder Kuai.
You know what?
A Tribulation is extremely dangerous
for cultivators.
You must handle it carefully.
But your vitals are all sealed.
And you can't use spiritual power.
When that lightning strikes down,
it's going to hurt like hell.
During my last Tribulation,
I noticed something.
The items you carry in tribulation
may affect
Fate's judgment of your cultivation.
It may even give you
a tribulation not meant for you.
I was afraid you'd be cold.
So I got you an Aureate Immortal's robe.
Changshou, I'm sorry.
Please let me go, Changshou.
It's all my fault.
For the sake of our sect ties...
Forgive me.
My dear Uncle, as your junior...
I picked the biggest Tribulation
for you.
No.
Enjoy it.
Gourd, help me.
Hello.
Thank you.
Reversal Cudgel.
How can this be?
A Deity.
[Hall of Mortal Coils]
Mentor.
Who is that?
That's...
Grand Mage of Voidcity.
♪I know the world's full of deceit♪
♪Put on a good show♪
♪Why not change forms and play♪
The thousand-year karmic debt...
♪Caught in karma, stained by dust♪
♪Say you're carefree♪
♪Yet still explore this fate♪
Beans into Soldiers.
♪In days to come, be God or Demon♪
♪Let them all come♪
♪There's a perfect plan for everything♪
♪Who's clamoring behind♪
♪Acting like fierce demons♪
♪I steadily divine the world's fate♪
♪Who plots and schemes♪
♪And set formations in the world♪
♪I will go in and stir things up♪
So powerful.
[Hall of Mortal Coils]
He's the Human Sect's top disciple.
A thousand years ago, he alone
brought down the Demon Clan.
I am Voidcity.
Top disciple of Lord Pureheaven.
Grand Mage of Voidcity?
What? Do you know him?
Not really.
Then why are you wowing?
He actually introduced himself to me.
Is she smiling at you?
You know her?
Not really.
Voidcity.
I'll make you remember
who I am.
You are
Little Gnat?
Oh no. They seem to know each other.
They're in cahoots?
This is
my karma.
Die!
Don't.
Freeze.
Where is this?
Grand Mage of Voidcity.
Your journey here
must have been hard.
I won't hurt you.
Go.
What?
Not leaving?
The Mortal Realm...
Is too dangerous for you.
Your coming here
is destiny
and karma.
Alright.
You can follow me from now on.
That's Grand Mage of Voidcity's blood.
Every drop
holds a century of cultivation.
Look.
This world
is so beautiful.
Perhaps...
This is human-gnat empathy.
It looks quite touching.
[Blood Sea]
Voidcity.
You killed my people.
[Blood Gnat Demon]
I'll end you!
I killed your people?
How many human lives have you taken?
In this Great Tribulation,
we were just two pawns.
Between us,
there is only mutual slaughter.
Until one side
is wiped out.
I'm sorry.
No!
Are you
going to kill me?
You're a deity.
I'm a demon.
We...
We have always been sworn foes.
We are enemies.
If you let me go today,
all you've done to us,
I'll repay you a hundredfold.
I'll kill all your people.
I'll destroy your sect.
I'll make you regret it for life.
Where is this?
The thousand-year karmic debt
is inescapable after all.
Grand Mage of Voidcity.
Ascendance Sect disciple Li Changshou
greets the Grand Mage of Voidcity.
Li Changshou.
Not Changgeng?
Changgeng is just my fake identity.
I dare not play tricks before you.
I see.
I boldly ask.
What I just saw...
Was it your memory?
Come with me.
So,
you knew that demon long ago?
Yes.
Did you
wipe out her clan?
Yes.
A thousand years have passed.
I can barely recall it now.
It's her.
This demon
manipulated Elder Kuai Si
into attacking his own sect,
leaving countless disciples dead.
She is
called Wen Jing.
She is a blood gnat,
born in the Blood Sea.
Her kind have lived there
for generations,
feeding on its blood
and keeping to themselves.
For the Blood Gnat Clan,
nothing matters more
than their own kind.
A gnat without its swarm
is pitifully insignificant.
But I
almost wiped out her entire clan.
All her sins are because of me.
She is my karmic debt.
My consequence to bear.
The few clansmen she has left
are all imprisoned in the Blood Sea.
Someone threatens her with their lives.
She was never evil at heart.
She only fell so low to save her clan.
Li Changshou.
I'm asking you to let her go.
Do you agree?
Grand Mage, do you know
what she has done?
Mentor Qi Yuan.
Aunt Wan Jiangyu.
Uncle Jiu Wu...
I know.
Changshou.
Let her go.
Can you?
Kuai Si.
[Jade Division]
Do you know what you are doing?
Detached Master
is dead?
You colluded with the Demon Clan,
killed the Grandlord,
and destroyed the Ascendance Sect.
I...
destroyed the Ascendance Sect?
Now in the Ascendance Sect,
only you and I are left.
How will you pay for this sin?
So that's how it is.
That demon saved me.
I won.
Decades of silent endurance.
I've finally seen this day.
Detached Master.
I finally defeated you.
Do you know
how long I've waited
for this day?
Ascendance Sect is no longer yours.
It's mine.
It belongs to Kuai Si!
You didn't win. You're crazy.
Ascendance Sect is gone.
Ascendance Sect is gone?
Isn't it all still here?
Look at the mountains, the land,
and the plants and dirt.
Aren't they all still here?
And look at me.
Aren't I still alive and well?
What are you talking about?
From this day forward,
I, Kuai Si,
am the Founding Patriarch
of the new Ascendance Sect.
You betrayed the sect and ancestors.
I aided the Westdawn Sect.
They will surely
help me rebuild the sect.
Westdawn Sect?
Right.
Westdawn Sect.
This attack on the mountain...
Wasn't the Great Tribulation
caused by the Seizing Sect
conspiring with the Demon Clan?
Seizing Sect?
Demon Clan?
What are they?
Just pawns in my hands.
From the very beginning...
From the very beginning,
it was me, Kuai Si,
controlling the whole Ascendance Sect.
Detached Master
didn't know the times
or see the big picture.
But I'm different.
With Westdawn's support,
the Ascendance Sect in my hands
will surely become the greatest sect.
The Three Sects won't just stand by.
Of course they won't.
But what a pity.
By that time, they'll be powerless
to stop Westdawn anymore.
Senior,
since you're about to die anyway,
I might as well tell you.
The Westdawn Sect's
about to open the Eye of the East Sea.
This will be a Great Tribulation.
All beings of the Three Sects,
barely one in ten will survive.
After the catastrophe,
if Westdawn strikes,
who can stop them?
Right.
Great Tribulation.
Senior.
Seeing that you've
had a hard life,
how about
I send you off early
to reunite with Wan Jiangyu?
That way,
you can avoid this Great Tribulation.
Sounds good?
I hate you the most.
Detached Master?
Grandlord.
Fellow cultivators.
Now,
the truth is out, right?
I'll take my leave.
Detached Master.
I am also an Aureate Immortal.
You want to kill me?
It won't be that easy.
Your opponent
isn't me.
Qi Yuan?
You harmed the Ascendance Sect.
It was me.
You ruined my foundation.
You killed my Senior Wan Jiangyu.
Also me.
Qi Yuan.
You're just trash
with a ruined foundation.
What can you do to me?
Everyone, follow me out.
It's going to get bloody here.
Senior. Mentor.
Let's go.
Kuai Si.
Your foundation was destroyed
by the lightning.
Remember?
You harmed the Ascendance Sect.
Ruined my foundation.
Killed my Senior.
It was me. All me.
You harmed the Ascendance Sect.
Ruined my foundation.
- Killed my Senior.
- Grandlord, save me!
You killed my Senior.
- Senior, I'm sorry.
- You killed my Senior!
Senior, it was all my fault.
You killed my Senior!
You're on your own.
[Hall of Mortal Coils]
Jiu Wu saw through Kuai Si's trick.
He went to Jade Division alone,
broke the formation with his life,
and got your magical power back
to defend the sect.
Jiu Wu.
You didn't let me down.
Jiu Jiu, neither did you.
Back then, my mind was fading.
I could only entrust this to you two.
Both of you
truly united the Three Sects.
I'm very proud.
Senior.
Is it because
I didn't urge Aunt Jiu Jiu to go?
That he...
I'm sorry.
It wasn't your fault.
Mentor was worried about us.
So he had Uncle Jiu Wu look after us.
♪Past fragments♪
You can never calculate the human heart.
♪See mortal joys and sorrows♪
♪Reunions and partings, as fate unfolds♪
♪Alas, love has many twists and turns♪
♪Memories filled with sorrow♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tearfully,
this life's bond is not over♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪
♪Down a few more cups of wine♪
♪Through land and sea,
I ask you to come♪
♪For honor's sake, upright and grand♪
♪Alas, our story is short♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tearfully,
this life's bond is not over♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪